# Michael Esti

Fairfax County, Virginia, United States



mestidesigns@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/michael-esti



(703) 888-8289



https://michaelesti-portfolio.netlify.app

## **Summary**

I am an UI/UX designer with +7 years of experience in visual design. I looking to transition my career out of sales. I love finding problems and coming up with solutions to them. I belong in the design industry and will do what ever it takes in order to improve.

## **Experience**



#### Visual Designer

Freelance

May 2016 - Present (6 years 1 month +)

- Graphic Design (logo design, illustrations, 3D design, branding, etc...).
- Web Design (wireframes, prototypes, limited front end coding abilities.)
- Mobile App Design (Design thinking, user experience design, user testing and research, wire framing, and prototyping).

## **CSS UX Designer**

Cost Savings Solutions

Mar 2021 - Jan 2022 (11 months)

Internal user experience designer. Tasked with streamlining sales methods and increasing revenue.



### Remodeling Consultant

Power Home Remodeling

Oct 2018 - Feb 2021 (2 years 5 months)

- Inspected and discovered issues with peoples' homes, explained issues in a simple easily understandable way, and persuaded homeowners to use our company to fix them.
- Over \$1.5 million in sales with a 35% closing rate, on one call close appointments.
- Utilized active listening and critical thinking, to decipher homeowners' wants and needs, and provide win-win solutions.

#### **Customer Service Associate**

Lowe's Companies, Inc.

Jan 2016 - Jul 2018 (2 years 7 months)

- Analyzed customer issues and provided optimal solutions to solve their problems.
- Maintained visual appeal of store merchandise.
- Developed innovative solutions to complex problems homeowners had with their home, with limited information.

#### ★ Marketing Associate

**CLEARED CONNECTIONS** 

Jun 2009 - Feb 2014 (4 years 9 months)

- Communicated with security cleared professionals in order to increase number of users.
- Increased customer base by attending job fairs at military bases.

#### **Education**

## **GW** The George Washington University

User Experience & Interface Design 2021 - 2022

#### **Radford University**

Business, Management, Marketing, and Related Support Services 2012 - 2016 (Did not complete)



#### **Bishop O'Connell High School**

2009 - 2012

#### **Licenses & Certifications**

<u>GW</u> User Experience Certification - The George Washington University

#### **Skills**

Graphic Design • Project Management • Analytical Skills • User Experience Design (UED) • User Interface Design • Figma (Software) • Adobe Creative Suite • Design Thinking • Prototyping • Wireframing